Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nhdiep (LinkedIn) www.facebook.com/ diepNIIT.nguyen (Other) github.com/diepnguyen87 (Other)

Top Skills

Appium

Mobile Testing

Test Automation

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Vietnamese (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Spring framework and dependency injection for beginners

Core Java

Diep Nguyen

Automation Tester

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Summary

Nearly 2 years of experience as a manual tester. Now I want to challenge myself with a new role - Java fresher. I went through a basic Java course on Coursera.

My Java knowledge is not really good but I want to find a place to practice and experience myself.

Experience

. . .

Automation Tester
July 2019 - Present (5 years 9 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Framework: Selenium, Appium

Imic Technology Center
Learner
July 2019 - September 2019 (3 months)
14 Phan Ton street, ward Dakao, district 1, HCM city

With this course, I try to reinforce my knowledge about java core and have opportunities to practice/build simply app together with younger classmates. The duration is 2,5 months for this course. After that I hope to get a offer as Java fresher at somewhere is able to train me more on Java EE or Java ME. Looking forward to hearing from you soon.

Tool: IntelliJ, Git

KMS Technology, Inc.

QA Engineer

October 2017 - June 2019 (1 year 9 months)

28 Truong Son street, ward 2, Tan Binh district, HCM city

Industry: healthcare

Device: handheld as mobile and tablet

Tools: Jira, Jama, qTest

Trung Tam Tin Hoc DH KHTN

4 months

Automated Testing

September 2017 - October 2017 (2 months)

137 Nguyen Chi Thanh street, ward 9, district 5, HCM city

Using Test Architect tool from Logigear for automation

Manual Testing

July 2017 - August 2017 (2 months)

137 Nguyen Chi Thanh street, ward 9, district 5, HCM city

Completed with 9.5/10

Have concepts in SDLC with some models as : Waterfall, Spiral, V model,

Concurrent and Agile;

Have knowledge in testing phrases with unit, integration, system and user acceptance testing;

Difference between Quality Assurance (QA), Quality Control (QC) and testing;

Practising some test case design techniques primarily in Equivalent Partioning and Boundary Analysis;

Building test cases from test requirements and bug lists;

Using exploratory testing to find new bugs on web apps

Using Testlink as test case management system and Bug Zilla as bug management system

vsource.io

Sourcer I

October 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 1 month)

District 12, Ho Chi Minh City

vsource is a talent acquisition platform combining smart technology with human intuition and recruiting experience.

Primary objective: assisting the company's clients in searching for any candidate profiles matching with jobs' requirements from online data sources and support them in building their internal data banks.

- Understanding client requirements and sourcing the suitable candidates for different positions.
- Searching & Short-listing the candidates as per client's requirements via jobboards, social networking sites (linkedin.com).
- Screening and short-listing CV's base on the remit provided.

- Identifying suitable candidates quickly for client submission.
- Submitting complete profile to Team Leader within given time.
- Getting new updating or tips from seniors or higher position regarding tough requirements.
- Doing some project tasks such as: doing career market research, building customer database, etc.
- Other duties assigned by Team Leader and Talent Sourcing Manager.

Industry: Internet, Information Technology and Services (IT), Computer Software, Staffing and Recruiting...

NIIT Limited Fulltime Student 2010 - 2012 (2 years) Vietnam

Implementing a database design on MS SQL Server 2005 OOPS Using C#

Developing windows applications using .NET Framework Introduction to Linux

Introduction to Java Programming language

Data Structures and Algorithms

Introduction to web content development (html, css)

Developing database application using ADO.NET & JDBC

Object oriented Analysis & design (OOAD and UML)

Developing web application using ASP.NET

Developing applications for the J2EE platform

Web Component development with Servlets and JSP technologies

Distributed application development using .NET framework

Education

Ho Chi Minh University of Agriculture and Forestry
Bachelor's Degree, Rural Development and Encourage Agricultural
Expansion · (2005 - 2009)

Coursera

Specialization (Duke University), Java Programming and Software Engineering Fundamentals · (2018)